A Finding Aid to the Blanche Lazzell Papers, 1893-1956, bulk 1901-1940, in the Archives of American Art AAA.lazzblan
Archives of American Art
Blanche Lazzell papers
bulk 1901-1940
1893-1986
AAA.lazzblan
Archives of American Art
4.6 Linear feet
The papers of printmaker, etcher, and painter Blanche Lazzell (1878-1956) measure 4.6 linear feet and date from 1893 to 1986, with the bulk of the material dating from 1901 to 1940. Found within the papers are biographical materials; correspondence with family, friends, and colleagues; writings; five diaries; scattered personal business records; printed material; artwork; photographs; and artifacts.
Lazzell, Blanche, 1878-1956
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged as 9 series.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1894-1970 (0.3 linear feet; Box 1)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1897-1965 (1.2 linear feet; Box 1-2)
Series 3: Writings, 1893-1969 (1.2 linear feet; Box 2-3)
Series 4: Diaries, 1896-1924 (0.1 linear feet; Box 3)
Series 5: Personal Business Records, 1894-1916 (0.1 linear feet; Box 3)
Series 6: Printed Material, 1899-1986 (1 linear feet; Box 3-4)
Series 7: Artwork, 1924-circa 1940 (0.1 linear feet; Box 4)
Series 8: Photographic Material, 1897-1956 (0.5 linear feet; Box 5-6)
Series 9: Artifacts, circa 1910-1956 (0.1 linear feet; Box 6)
Biographical/Historical note
Blanche Lazzell (1878-1956) was a printmaker, etcher, painter, and rug designer who worked primarily in Provincetown, Massachusetts and Morgantwon, West Virginia.
Nettie Blanche Lazzell was born in Maidsville, West Virginia, in 1878, the daughter of Mary Prudence Pope and Cornelius Carhart Lazzell. At some point during her childhood, Lazzell became partially deaf. When Lazzell was fifteen, she enrolled in the West Virginia Conference Seminary, now West Virginia Wesleyan College and graduated in 1898.
In 1899, Lazzell continued her studies at the South Carolina Co-educational Institute and graduated that same year. She later matriculated into the West Virginia University (1901-1905) where she took drawing and art history classes with William J. Leonard and earned a degree in fine arts. After graduation, Lazzell periodically studied at the university until 1909. Lazzell moved to New York City in 1907 and enrolled in the Art Students League of New York in 1908 where she studied under William Merritt Chase.
Lazzell travelled to Europe during the summer of 1912. After visiting several cities, Lazzell went to Paris and stayed beyond the tour to attend classes at the Académie Julian and the Académie Moderne where she studied with painter Charles Guérin. Lazzell returned to the United States in the fall of 1913 and stayed in West Virginia with her sister Bessie. She held a solo exhibition of her sketches and paintings in 1914. Lazzell moved to the thriving art colony at Provincetown, Massachusetts in 1915. There, she studied with Charles Webster Hawthorne, who founded the Cape Cod School of Art, and Oliver Chaffee, who taught her the technique for white-line woodcuts. Lazzell quickly adopted and excelled at making white-line woodblock prints, joined the Provincetown Printers, an art collective, and regularly exhibited with them.
n 1918, Lazzell converted an "old fish house" overlooking the Provincetown harbor into her studio and summer home. She planted a lush garden that became a tourist attraction where she often hosted teas and taught classes on painting and woodblock printing. The studio became her primary summer residence, though she often returned to Morgantown, West Virginia. Lazzell also visited other artist colonies during this time, including one in Woodstock, New York where she studied with Andrew Dasburg.
In 1919 Lazzell was featured in an exhibition at Touchstone Gallery in New York City. Later that year, the Provincetown Printers were featured at the Detroit Institute of Arts exhibition "Wood Block Prints in Color by American Artists". That show included Lazzell's depiction of the Monongahela River in Morgantown.
From 1923 to 1924, Lazzell travelled again to Europe and studied with Fernand Legér, André Lhote, and Albert Gleizes in Paris. Lazzell studied Cubism and took a class with Gleizes and her work became more abstract. When she returned to Provincetown, she had her studio rebuilt so it was more comfortable during the winter. She continued to teach art at her studio and participate in exhibitions.
In addition to her woodblock prints, Lazzell also worked with batik, rug design, and hand-painted china. She was a member of numerous arts organizations such as the Société Anonyme, New York Society of Women Artists, Provincetown Art Association, the Sail Loft Club (a Provincetown women's art club), and the Society of Independent Artists. In 1934, Lazzell received a Federal Art Project grant through the Works Progress Administration and created a mural titled Justice for the Morgantown courthouse.
Lazzell died in Morgantown, West Virginia in 1956.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center. Contact Reference Services for more information.
Separated Materials note
The papers were originally loaned for microfilming on reels 2988-2991 and most of them, but not all, were included in a later donation. The papers not included in the later donation are only available on microfilm.
Existence and Location of Copies note
The collection was microfilmed on 35 mm microfilm reels 2988-2991, available at Archives of American Art offices and through interlibrary loan. Researchers are advised that the filmed order does not reflect the current order of the collection as described in this finding aid.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Blanche Lazzell papers were anonymously donated to the Archives of American Art in 1987, including most of the materials that had been earlier loaned for microfilming in 1983.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of printmaker, etcher, and painter Blanche Lazzell (1878-1956) measure 4.6 linear feet and date from 1893 to 1986, with the bulk of the material dating from 1901 to 1940. Found within the papers are biographical materials; correspondence with family, friends, and colleagues; writings; five diaries; scattered personal business records; printed material; artwork; photographs; and artifacts.
Biographical material includes school report cards, address books, obituaries, membership certificates, and travel documents from Blanche Lazzell's travels abroad in Europe.
Correspondence is with family, friends, and colleagues. Family correspondence is predominately with Lazzell's sisters, and a lesser amount with her brother Rufus and other relatives. Well over one-half of the correspondence is with friends and colleagues, including Arthur Lee Post and John O' Connor, and one or more letters from Oliver Chaffee, Andrew Dasburg, Robert Henri, and Ralph M. Pearson, among others.
Writings include notebooks, essays, and notes. Notebooks are primarily class notes, including one from Lazzells's studies in France during her second trip to Europe, and another maintained as a record of artwork. Also found are essays,including one about Provincetown; notes; biographical sketches; and lists of exhibitions and artwork. Five diaries document the late 1890s and Lazzell's trips to Europe in 1912-1913 and 1923-1924.
Scattered personal business records consist of 3 expense account ledgers and one sales ledger. Printed Material includes guest books, news clippings, exhibition catalogs, exhibition announcements, magazines, brochures, and newsletters. Artwork includes pencil drawings and sketches, mostly from studies with the artist Albert Gleizes in Paris. Photographic material consists of photographs, slides, and one lantern slide. The photographs are of Blanche Lazzell with artists and friends, her studio and the harbor in Provincetown, artwork, and travels in Italy.
Artifacts include 2 metal signs and 1 paint palette in a metal case.
Separated Materials note
Portions of the microfilmed material were retained by the donor.
Chaffee, Oliver Newberry, 1881-1944; Dasburg, Andrew, 1887-1979; Gleizes, Albert, 1881-1953; Henri, Robert, 1865-1929; O'Connor, John; Pearson, Ralph M., 1883-1958; Art--Study and teaching; Artists' studios--Photographs; Diaries; Drawings; Etchers; Etching--Massachusetts--Provincetown; Painters; Painting--Massachusetts--Provincetown; Photographs; Printmakers; Sketches; Visitors books; Women artists
- Biographical Material, 1894-1970; Series 1; 0.3 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical material includes school report cards from West Virginia Conference Seminary and West Virginia University, 2 address books, obituaries, membership certificates, and assorted travel documents from Blanche Lazzell's trips to Europe.
  - West Virginia Conference Seminary Report Cards, 1894-1898 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - West Virginia University Report Cards, 1902-1910 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Membership Certificates, 1896-1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Europe Trip Printed Material, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Europe Trip Receipts and Expenses, 1912-1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Address Book, circa 1913 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Address Book, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Obituaries for Siblings, 1931-1955 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Family History, circa 1956-1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Blanche Lazzell Estate Papers, circa 1956 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Blanche Lazzell Obituary, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Short Biographical Profiles, circa 1958 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1897-1965; Series 2; 1.2 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  Correspondence is with family members, friends, and colleagues.
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged as 2 subseries.
  2.1: Family Correspondence, 1899-1956
  2.2: Friends and Colleagues, 1897-1965
  - Family Correspondence, 1899-1956; 2.1
    The bulk of the Lazzell's family correspondence is with her sisters on the subject of daily life, experiences, and travels. There is also additional scattered correspondence with her brother Rufus and other relatives, such as her niece Frances Reed.
    The correspondence with Lazzell's sisters are grouped together at the beginning of the series and arranged chronologically. The letters with her sisters were not alphabetized since they were frequently addressed "Dear Sister" and did not specify the recipient's name, though Lazzell often wrote to her younger sister Bessie. The rest of the subseries is arranged alphabetically, starting with an aunt and uncle who are only given nicknames.
    - Correspondence with Sisters, 1896-1956 (Box 1, Folder 13-20)
    - "Aunt Jo", circa 1901 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - "Barkis", 1901-1903 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      "Barkis" is probably an uncle. The nickname is from David Copperfield.
    - Lazzell, B. F., 1927 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Lazzell, Rufus F., 1899-1919 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Lazzell, Delmar, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Lazzell, Mrs. Charles, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Lazzell, Nellie, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Reed, James Cornelius and Janet, 1926-1954 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Sellers, Frances Reed, 1923-1953 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Taylor, Grace Martin (Frame), 1932-1942 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Friends and Colleagues, 1897-1965; 2.2
    The bulk of the correspondence with friends is with Arthur Lee Pos. Additional scattered correspondence is with friends and colleages, including artists Oliver Chaffee, Andrew Dasburg, Robert Henri, and Ralph M. Pearson, among others. There is also limited correspondence with museums and art organizations, such as the Société Anonyme, of which Lazzell was a member, and one folder of acceptance and rejection notices from exhibitions. regarding artwork Blanche Lazzell submitted.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically. Prominent artists and individuals with three or more letters have individual named folders. Unidentified correspondents, holiday cards, and notices about exhibition submissions are arranged at the end of the series.
    - Anthony, Mrs. Harvey C., 1927-circa 1932 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - A-B, Miscellaneous, 1911-1948 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Cain Family, 1899-1903 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Correspondence from W. O., Lois, Ida, Ruth, and Jameson Cain.
    - Chaffee, Oliver, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      Letters from Lois, Ida, Ruth, Jameson, and W. O. Cain.
    - C, Miscellaneous, 1898-1944 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Dasburg, Andrew, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Dwight Family, 1900-1941 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      Includes correspondence from Annie, Frank, and Mary Dwight.
    - D, Miscellaneous, 1901-1934 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - E-F, Miscellaneous, 1908-1943 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Grant, Justin F., 1939-1945 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - G, Miscellaneous, 1942-1955 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Henri, Robert, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - H, Miscellaneous, 1897-1945 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - J-K, Miscellaneous, 1897-1934 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Leonard, William J., 1917 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - de Liva, H., 1913-1916 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - L, Miscellaneous, 1903-1910 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Marshall, Emma R., 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - McCormick, Katherine H., 1943-1953 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - M-N, Miscellaneous, 1900-1939 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - New York World's Fair, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - O'Connor, John, Jr., 1934-1948 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Pearson, Ralph M., 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Post, Arthur Lee, 1890-1900 (Box 1, Folder 54-57)
    - Post, Arthur Lee, 1901-1906 (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
    - Post, Arthur Lee - Undated, circa 1895-1906 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - P, Miscellaneous, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Ramsey Family, 1900-1901 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Includes correspondence from Boyce, Tallulah, and Hattie Ramsey.
    - R, Miscellaneous, 1898-1934 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Schanzenbacher, Nellie, 1908-1912 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Smith, Simeon Earnest and Mother, 1921-1923 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Société Anonyme, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - S, Miscellaneous, 1898-1942 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - T, Miscellaneous, 1933-1941 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - W, Miscellaneous, 1930-circa 1965 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Young, M. G., 1923 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Y, Miscellaneous, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified Correspondents, 1897-1955 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Partial Undated Letters, circa 1900-circa 1940 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Fragments of letters written by Blanche Lazzell with dates and names of correspondents missing.
    - Notices for Exhibition Submissions, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Christmas Cards, 1924-1961 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Writings, 1893-1969; Series 3; 1.2 Linear feet Boxes 2-3
  Writings include notebooks, essays, and notes. The bulk of the notebooks contain class notes from Lazzell's classes at West Virginia Conference Seminary and West Virginia University. There is also one notebook from Lazzell's art studies with Albert Gleizes in Paris and one notebook that tracks time spent and progress made on prints and works in progress, with some information about pricing. Essays and notes consist of school papers, handwritten and typed drafts of essays on art, biographical sketches, lists and inventories of exhibitions and artwork, and miscellaneous notes.
  3.1: Notebooks, 1893-1937
  3.2: Essays and Notes, 1899-1969
  - Notebooks, 1893-1937; 3.1
    - Untitled School Notebook, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - West Virginia Conference Seminary Notebook, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - West Virginia Conference Seminary Notebook, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - West Virginia Conference Seminary Notebook, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - West Virginia University Notebooks (Box 2)
      - 17th Century Literature Notebook, 1901-1911 (Box 2, Folder 25)
        Mostly class notes, but also includes a few pages at the end of the notebook on sales of handpainted "china pins" in 1911.
      - 17th Century Literature Notebook, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Chapel 47 Notebook, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Botany Notebook, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 28)
        Includes a few drawings of budding branches.
      - Chapel 49 Notebook, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Chapel 51 Notebook, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Literature: The Elizabethan Period Notebook, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Literature: The Classic Period Notebook, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Literature 15 Notebook, 1902-1903 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Literature 17 Notebook, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - History of Greek Art Notebooks, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 35-36)
      - History of Roman and Modern Art Notebooks, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 37-38)
    - West Virginia University Notebooks (Box 3)
      - 19th Century Literature Notebook, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Art History Notebook, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Bible as Literature Notebook, circa 1904 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Art History Notebook, 1906 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Loose Pages School Notebooks, circa 1901-1904 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Untitled Notebook, 1902-1934 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Mostly school notes from 1902-1904, but also includes several pages used as a studio guest list from 1930-1934.
    - "Measurements in Paintings" Notebook, circa 1923 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Notebook is written in French, possibly from a class with Albert Gleizes, and includes several sketches.
    - Art Record Book, 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Essays and Notes, 1899-1969; 3.2
    - School Papers, 1899-1904 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Essays on Art, 1912-circa 1939 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - "Some Palaces of Florence", circa 1925 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - "The Color Wood Block Print", 1929 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Notes on the Creativity of Children, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Wood Block Print Exhibitions List, 1931-1953 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Biographical Sketch, 1931-circa 1953 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Biographical Notes, circa 1934-1955 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - "Creative Design" Essay on Rugs and Fabrics, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - "The Provincetown Print" Drafts, circa 1935-1953 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Compilations of Publicity and Notes, circa 1937-1956 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      Includes retyped excerpts from reviews of Blanche Lazzell's work along with other notes.
    - Miscellaneous Notes, circa 1925-circa 1952 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - "On a Provincetown Dock" by Mary A. Kirkup, circa 1920 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - "Metamorphic Progressions of Shape" by Stanley E. Shafer, circa 1969 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Diaries, 1896-1924; Series 4; 0.1 Linear feet Box 3
  There are five bound diaries and a few loose scattered diary entries. Three of the diaries are from Lazzell's first trip to Europe from 1912 to 1913, one of which also includes entries about her second trip to Europe in 1923-1924. There is also a guidebook heavily annotated by Lazzell with information about itineraries and and locations of interest.
  - Diary, 1896 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Loose Pages from Diaries, 1897-1902 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Diary, 1899 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - "My Winter in Paris" Travel Diary, 1912-1913 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Europe Travel Diary, 1912-1913 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Europe Travel Diary, 1912-1934 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    Includes entries about first Europe trip and second trip from 1923-1924.
  - Europe Guidebook with Annotations, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Personal Business Records, 1894-1916; Series 5; 0.1 Linear feet Box 3
  Personal business records consist of 3 ledgers that list Lazzell's expenses beginning in her early school years at the West Virginia Conference Seminary, and one book tracking the sales and expenses for hand-painted china.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Expense Account Ledger, 1894-1897 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Expense Account Ledger, 1902-1905 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Expense Account Ledger, 1905-1915 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Account Book for Handpainted China Expenses and Sales, 1903-1916 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Printed Material, 1899-1986; Series 6; 1 Linear feet Boxes 3-4
  Printed material includes guestbooks of visitors to exhibitions and Lazzell's studio, news clippings, exhibition catalogs for solo and group shows, exhibition announcements, assorted magazines, brochures, newsletters, and other miscellaneous material. Most but not all of the clippings and catalogs include references to Blanche Lazzell and her art.
  - Painting Exhibitions Guestbook, 1914-1916 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Blanche Lazzell Studio Guestbook, 1926-1936 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Loose Pages from Wood Block Print Exhibition Guest Sign-In, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1904-1982 (Box 4, Folder 2-8)
  - Undated Newspaper Clippings, circa 1910-1956 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings, circa 1910-1972 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Magazine Articles, 1927-1986 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Blanche Lazzell Exhibition Catalogs, 1914-1957 (Box 4, Folder 12-14)
    Includes catalogs for solo shows and group exhibitions that Lazzell participated in.
  - Exhibition Catalogs for Other Artists, 1913-1957 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Blanche Lazzell Exhibition Announcements, 1914-1985 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Exhibition Announcements for Other Artists, circa 1923 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - School Arts, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Art News, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - West Virginia University Magazine, 1972-1981 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Pittsburgher Magazine, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Provincetown Brochures, 1915-circa 1974 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - The Student Newsletters, 1912-1914 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Bulletin of the Detroit Institute of Arts, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Vedanta Quarterly, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Pamphlets and Programs, 1899-1952 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Blanche Lazzell Exhibit Poster, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Press Releases, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1907-1954 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Artwork, 1924-circa 1940; Series 7; 0.1 Linear feet Box 4
  Artwork includes pencil drawings from a class with Albert Gleizes during Lazzell's second trip to Paris in 1924. The drawings and sketches include annotations by Lazzell along with some class notes. There is also one folder of miscellaneous, undated sketches.
  - Pencil Drawings from Albert Gleizes Class, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Sketches from "The Golden Section and Mathematics in Art", circa 1924 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous Sketches, circa 1924-circa 1940 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Photographic Material, 1897-1956; Series 8; 0.5 Linear feet Boxes 5-6
  This series includes photographs, slides, and one lantern slide. Most of the photographs are black and white, with a few in color, and they show Blanche Lazzell with artists and friends, her Provincetown studio and harbor, artwork, and travels in Italy.
  The materials are grouped first by format, such as prints and slides, then by subjects in chronological order.
  - Blanche Lazzell and Lotta Kemp, circa 1897 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - West Virginia University Group Outing at Coopers Rock, 1905 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Italy Trip, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Italian Art from Italy Trip, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Blanche Lazzell and Friends, 1923-1950 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Includes photographs of Blanche Lazzell alone and accompanied by friends, a few while traveling in Italy, but mostly at outside her Provincetown studio.
  - Provincetown Wharf and Boats, 1926-1946 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Includes photographs of the Provincetown wharf, harbor, and shore near Lazzell's studio.
  - Photographs of Blanche Lazzell's Artwork, circa 1925-1956 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Artwork Photographed on Site at Provincetown, 1927-1951 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Includes photographs of artwork at various locations in Provincetown such as inside Lazzell's studio and at Hans Hofmann's class.
  - Provincetown Studio Exterior, 1933-1954 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Justice Mural at Courthouse in Morgantown, West Virginia, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 10)